John Bedeir

DevOps Engineer

- +4591481268
- john.bedeir@gmail.com
- www.johnydev.com
- Copenhagen, Denmark

SUMMARY

I am a skilled DevOps Engineer with 3+ years of hands-on experience and a total of 10 years of experience, an expert in Debian, RedHat, Unix & Windows OS with a strong development background.

My target is to master the DevSecOps culture, currently, I am focusing on applying Build, Test, maintaining the infrastructure to speed up the development and release process using CI /CD, Network, Security, and Cloud services.

My previous roles in the IT field started with providing level 1 and level 2 technical support as a System Administrator, troubleshooting, and maintenance of the technology infrastructure and systems for endpoint device management.

Then I became an IT Manager, which was more managerial level than technical, starting with identifying the need for upgrades, configurations, or new systems, assigning tasks, monitoring the project pipeline, during this time I was preparing myself to be a DevOps engineer.

EXPERIENCE

DevOps Engineer 10/2021 - Present

PSQR (Copenhagen, Denmark)

Applying GitOps

- Working with Digital Ocean & GCP
- · Monitoring using Prometheus & Grafana
- · Using Terraform & Pulumi for IAC
- Build, Test & Deploy using Jenkins.
- Other Tools: JFrog | Cassandra | ScyllaDB | RabbitMQ | MariaDB & ZooKeeper.
- Project 1: Build testing environment for Ubuntu 18.04 & Ubuntu 20.04 using Ansible
- · Project 2: Build Switch configuration using Terraform
- Project 3: Build an automated testing environment that works on both Debian & RedHat using Ansible

DevOps Engineer 01/2020 - 09/2021

Orange Business Services (Cairo, Egypt)

Orange Business Services is a French multinational telecommunications corporation.

- Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery
- Working in Software development life cycle
- · Working in AGILE & Concept of Infrastructure as a Code.
- Participating in Front-End Development.
- · Integrate Maven, Tomcat, Gitlab with Jenkins
- Project-1: Using Docker to containerize a web app
- Project-2: Build CI/CD automation with GitLab for web app
- Project-3: Manage all build and deploy tools, and oversee all deployments using Kubernetes, Ansible & Jenkins
- Project-4: Working with AWS using (EC2, IAM, Security Groups, etc.)
- Project-5: Django app & environment setup, Gitlab CI/CD, Jenkins, AWS Deployment
- Project-6: PHP, Laravel environment setup, integrating Jenkins with Gitlab CI/CD, AWS Deployment.
- Project-7: Integrating Jenkins and Maven with Gitlab, setup Tomcat Server and use Docker, Ansible & Kubernetes in CI/CD Pipeline.
- Project-8: Setting up Kubernetes Cluster, EC2, Route53, S3 Bucket, and IAM on AWS with Deploy and Service using Terraform & Ansible

1/3

IT Manager 09/2018 - 09/2019

Yarvor Technologies (Dubai, UAE)

YARYOR is a small company, mostly working on projects that include new technologies like Robotics, Virtual Reality, Augmented Reality, Digital Signages, Web Development, and Mobile applications.

- · Managing 5 employees
- · Monitor performance of information technology systems to determine cost and productivity levels
- · Handle annual budget and ensure cost-effectiveness
- Creating scripts to automate tasks

Senior System Administrator

03/2016 - 04/2018

Plus500 BG (Sofia, Bulgaria)

Plus 500 is a global fintech firm providing online trading services, I started there as a Technical Support then I've been promoted to Senior System Administrator providing High-level Support for Windows OS in 2 offices, NUC's hardware replacement, CISCO switches, routers, and alternative cloud servers.

- Provide 24/7 Level 2 Support across all facilities.
- Ensure that helpdesk tickets are closed or escalated promptly.
- Ensure there are no alerts in the Symantec endpoint console.
- Monitoring the Server room temperature via sensor.
- · Performs other related duties as assigned.

Senior System Administrator

01/2014 - 07/2015

Aroma Studios (Cairo, Egypt)

AROMA is an extraordinary company for media production in the middle east I joined them as a Senior System Administrator providing 24/7 coverage with level 2 crossover platform support Windows, LINUX & UNIX.

- Level 1 2 Support for all instances (on location, via phone & remotely)
- Install and configure Linux / Unix and perform system maintenance.
- Ensure assigned & pending tasks have been solved.
- Ensure there are no alerts in the Kaspersky endpoint security management console.
- Check the Servers & Render-farm room temperature.
- · Performs other related duties as assigned

System Administrator

09/2011 - 12/2013

Arabcomed (Cairo, Egypt)

The Arab Company for Medical Products is a factory for manufacturing pharmaceuticals as a System Administrator this was my first full-time job after graduation providing level 1 support for Installing, troubleshooting Windows OS, and hardware replacement.

- · Level 1 Support on location, via phone or remotely,
- Ensure all the endpoint devices are working properly.
- · Software & Hardware Troubleshooting.

EDUCATION

Computer Science and Engineering (Cloud Computing)

2019

Technical University (Sofia, Bulgaria) - Masters Degree

Computer Science

2011

Future Academy (Cairo, Egypt) - Bachelor's Degree

Volunteering Activity

2007

Enactus Organization (Cairo, Egypt) - Member of IT Committee

SKILLS

Windows OS / Linux / Unix **Jenkins** Intermediate Expert Docker / Vagrant Expert Python | REST API Intermediate Intermediate **Bash Scripting** Expert JavaScript Virtualization Expert Grafana / Prometheous Beginner

Git, Github, Gitlab & Bitbucket Expert JFrog

Web Hosting Expert ScyllaDB / MariaDB

Apache, Nginx Expert RabbitMQ
HTML5 / CSS3 Expert ZooKeeper

Kubernetes | HELM Advanced Digital Ocean / GCP

Ansible Advanced ELK
RHCSA / RHCSE Advanced Tekton
AWS Intermediate GitOps
Terraform Intermediate Pulumi

LANGUAGES

Arabic Native Bulgarian Basic

English Fluent